Frewoini Gebremichael

(404) 906-0388 / frewoinit945@gmail.com/ Long Beach, California

linkedin.com/in/frewoini-gebremichael-479940233| https://github.com/Frewoini

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Dedicated, passionate and detailed oriented full stack java developer with 460+ training hours and experience in developing full stack Java applications. Interested in attaining a career that will allow me the opportunity to excel in software development as well as highlight my previous work experience and teamwork abilities.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

W3Schools JavaScript Certification (in progress; expected date of completion 07/2022)

- Java
- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS
- Spring Boot

- Spring Data JPA
- Spring Security (JWT)
- Bootstrap
- REST API's
- SQL

- Unit Testing (JUnit, Mockito)
- SOLID OOP Principles
- Dependencies Injection
- Git

EXPERIENCE

Generation Junior Full Stack Java Developer Program | Mar 2022- July 2022

- Participating in a 16-week, 460+ hour Junior Full Stack Java Developer program that emphasizes hands-on practical application
- Learning and deploying the technologies involved in creating full stack web applications with Java using Spring Boot Framework, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3
- Implementing basic unit tests and deploying the application to Heroku

Ethiopian Airlines | Addis Ababa Ethiopia | May 2013 - Dec. 2019

Aircraft Maintenance Planning Engineer

- Experienced with Aircraft Maintenance long/short term planning and scheduling heavy maintenance Checks for different aircraft models.
- Coordinate material support requirements for routine and non-routine items, Coordinate repair/alteration plans with Materials/Purchasing.
- Accomplished 4.5 out of 5 in KPI(Key Performance Indicator) and was awarded 2 months' salary.

Ethiopian Airlines | Addis Ababa Ethiopia| May 05, 2011 - April 2013

Aircraft Maintenance Technician

• Maintaining and inspecting aircraft airframe systems and assist in dispatching aircraft.

EDUCATION

Bahir Dar University, Bahir Dar, Ethiopia

B.Sc. Degree in Industrial Engineering

Ethiopian Aviation Academy, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Associate Degree and License on Airframe Maintenance